Phemelo Motsamai

Johannesburg

Email: phemelojmotsamai@gmail.com . Cell: 0848364284 / 0762214934

Professional Summary

I have learned to bridge between business requirements and development translation and the importance of developing usable & meaningful software products. I also understand the importance of support engineering to the client once software you have rendered software as a service to the client.

I have over the years gathered learning and practical experience from learnerships and internships that earned me foundation experience in Low code engineering (https://www.alphasoftware.com) & Back End Server-side scripting, with JAVA (Enterprise Edition), PHP(Apache) development through object-oriented design principles.

I have an adequate foundation understanding of software documentation in reference to database design (ERD Diagramming) and other unified modeling language systems diagramming (Activity Diagrams, Use Cases, Sequence Diagrams).

Education

Diploma In IT Software Development

NQF Level 6 2016 - 2018

IIE Rosebank college Braamfontein

National Certificate: Information Technology

Systems Development 2019 - 2020

NQF Level 5

JumpCo Software Labs

High School Degree 2015

Immaculata Secondary School

Professional Experience

1st

Intern Low Code & Support Engineer

December 2021 - June 2022.

Place Mazia EVP.

Address 73 Vessels, Rivonia. Website <u>https://maziaevp.com.</u>

Duties

- Designing Low code applications with Alpha Transform (https://www.alphasoftware.com).
- Documenting business specification requirements for client software solutions.
- Translating and converting paper forms to data collection electronic mobile software.
- Documenting the requirements of Migrating Legacy data to new systems.
- Implementation of dashboarding and reporting for software solutions.
- Design workflows as part of software documentation.
- Signi-Flow implementation.
- Software project management through Agile Methodologies and JIRA Cloud as technology.
- Software unit testing.
- Microsoft Office 365 administration managing employees as users of systems and software licenses.
- ICT support.
- I introduced Trello to the organization to manage projects.
- I introduced Zapier to automate small repetitive tasks.
- Xero quotations and billing of SLA (Service Level Agreements) services.
- Fleetio software implementation engineering for fleet Industry clients.

2nd

WordPress developer

June 2021 - November 2021.

Place Ntumba Inc.

Address 73 Vessels, Rivonia.

Website https://coachtime.co.za/internship

https://ntumba.co.za

November 2019 - 2020.

Jumpco Software labs.

Duties

• Administrating cPanel and Administrating WordPress as a super user.

- Monitor website uptime.
- Preparing website user stories.
- Converting WordPress to android/iOS application.
- Research and choose suitable plugins for new features.
- Agile development and experience with Trello and GitHub.
- Designing social walls.
- Designing with ninja forms.
- Designing news feeds.
- Implementing Buddypress.
- Designing with Elementor and Newspaper 9.
- PHP and Html development (editing plug-Ins).
- Monitor MySQL Database.

3rd

Java EE Developer (Learnership MICT SETA)

Place

Address Randburg.

Projects GitHub gh repo clone PhemeloMotsamai/clocksheet

Duties

- Data Modelling.
- Web development Java EE 7.
- Project Management.
- Database (MySQL, MS SQL SERVER) DML, DDL.
- Consuming Maven Libraries.
- Attained NQF Level 5 in systems development at the end of learnership.

Skills

- I have a solid understanding of the importance of user experience and user interface design.
- I have an excellent understanding of research before asking for help and am proficient in working in a team.
- Ability to work under pressure and not panic but have the patience to find solutions.

Reference

Contact Name Position Contact Number Company

Contact Name Position Contact Number Company

Contact Name Position Contact Number Company Mike Nelushi. Senior Developer. +27 21 825 9725. Mazia EVP.

John Maunde. Supervisor. +27 11 326 6270. Ntumba Inc.

Valdy Walters.
Facilitator.
+27 11 431 1667.
Jumpco Software Labs.